

Queens, NY

□ (+1) 347-430-3398 | Machristianmsakai@gmail.com | Onchristiansakai | Christiansakai | Ch

Summary _

Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience specializing in fullstack web development. A vim + tmux + zsh + OSX user. Interests in web development, programming languages, compilers, systems development, data, and functional programming. Aspire to continuously self-improve toward more challenging backend work. Play guitar, bass and sing to keep myself creative, practice karate to keep myself healthy.

Skills

Proficient JavaScript/TypeScript, HTML & CSS, Angular, React, Redux, NodeJS, MongoDB, Webpack, Grunt, Gulp, Git

Knowledgeable Elixir, Phoenix, Ecto, PostgreSQL, Sass, Haskell, Elm, ETFX, AWS, Docker, D3

Basic C, C++, Java, Lisp

Work Experience _____

IrisVR Inc.

New York City

SOFTWARE ENGINEER CONSULTANT Oct. 2016 - PRESENT

- · Implemented efficient build system on company's front end and desktop app development environment using Webpack
- Designed failure-point handling to handle disconnections between several NodeJS backend services gracefully
- Migrated company's MongoDB and AWS Redshift database changes with ensured consistency
- Built an offline open source analytics caching library to preserve analytics in case of unavailable connection for company's desktop app
- Worked on various features on company's front end and desktop app

FactorSpot Maryland

SOFTWARE ENGINEER CONSULTANT

VARIOUS CONTRACT DATES

- Designed security policy over company's Firebase data
- Integrated Intuit's Quickbook API to company's backend
- Built Bobtail fullstack web app using Elixir and Phoenix

Ninthbeat Inc.

New York City

Co-founder & Software Engineer Mar. 2015 - Dec. 2015

- Built company's web app using MEAN stack
- Built company's smartphone app using Ionic

Fullstack Academy New York City

TEACHING FELLOW Jul. 2014 - Feb. 2015

- · Assisted instructors on lecture
- Designed a Grunt workshop for students
- Assisted and reviewed student projects
- Built company's internal social media platform web app

Education _

Queens College Flushing, NY

M.A. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE 2016 - 2018

Alliance Theological Seminary Manhattan, NY

M.Div. in Theological Studies 2010 - 2013

Bina Nusantara University

Jakarta, Indonesia

B.Eng. in Industrial Engineering 2004 - 2008

FEBRUARY 12, 2018 CHRISTIAN SAKAI · RÉSUMÉ